PROFESSOR: I would like to give
you some advice on how to choose
good names for your variables.
In this example program, I
chose the variable name balance,
and then gave it a value of
50, because balance represents
how much money is in my bank account.
Here in this printf statement,
you see, it'll print out, I have--
percent d. The percent d is replaced with 50.
That's stored in balance.
I have $50 in my bank account.
So that's why I chose this
variable named balance.
It is an explicit name
that says something
about what's the work in this variable.
So the first rule is to
choose an explicit name.
But there are certain restrictions
in C, on your variable names.
And I'll put those in a
comment right up here.
Variable names can use
lowercase and uppercase letters,
(or characters) and digits.
But they cannot use special characters
such as the at sign, or the pound sign,
of the ampersand sign, and so forth.
They can also not use accented
letters, like e with an accent on it.
And-- it's an important one--
they cannot start with a digit.
So they have to start with a letter.
Spaces are also forbidden
in variable names.
So if you wanted to call
the variable my balance,
you could not type my space balance.
However, an underscore may
be used instead of a space,
in the name of a variable.
And so how do you do that, if you
want to have a variable name that
consists of several
words, you can't simply
stick all those words together
using uppercase letters
between the words instead of spaces.
So you can use uppercase letters
between words and set of spaces.
So let's look at some examples.
Suppose you wanted to call this
a valid balance for that balance.
You can't just say valid space balance.
That is an illegal variable name.
If I were to tried to compile
this, it would actually
give me an error message.
What you can do instead
is place an underscore
instead of the space character.
Now, valid_balance, with the
underscore in the middle,
is a legal variable name.
Of course, I'll have to update it
all over the place in my program,
otherwise my program doesn't know
that I just chose a new variable name.
And now that I did that, I can
actually compile and run this program.
And it runs just fine.
I have $50 in my bank account.
There are other ways to deal with
the fact that you cannot use spaces.
One of them is you just
get rid of the underscore.
But now, that's really hard to read.
And so what you can do
instead is to just uppercase
the beginning letter of a next word.
So validBalance here,
with a B upper cased,
indicates that I really meant two
words, but I couldn't do that.
And now, if I change this
all over the place again,
then my program runs just fine.
I just replaced my variable
with this new variable.
So let's check this
out, compile, and run.
And it works just fine.
I have $50 in my bank account.
It's a personal preference on whether
you prefer to use an underscore
or just smack your words right
together by upper casing in the middle.
It's a real personal preference.
It's up to you.
But what's really
important-- you need to be
explicit with your variable names.
Choose names that indicate
what the variable is all about
and what it's used for, so
that people reading your code
can understand it more easily.
And in addition, your variable names
need to follow all of the rules
that we just saw above.