PROFESSOR: How do you vary
the value of a variable?
That's what I'm going to show
you in this codecast.
I'm going to do an example of
a bank account with a balance,
and we will vary the
value of this balance.
So first, I'm going to create,
that is declare, a variable
that can contain integer values.
And the name is balance.
So here creating a variable
containing integer values.
And I'm going to assign the
value 50, meaning that first, I
put $50 in my bank account,
so assigning the value
$50 into the balance variable.
And then I'm going to print.
I have percent d dollars
in my account, new line,
and I want to show the value
of the variable balance.
Let's compile and run the program.
I have $50 in my account.
That's the output of the
program in the terminal.
Good.
Now, I'm going to show you how we
can vary the value of this variable.
Let's try to do a next balance of $40.
So I mean that I want to
reassign another time,
the same variable balance,
but with a new value.
So I could do something like this.
balance equals
I assign the new value
10, which means I had 50.
I do an expense of 40, then I have 10.
Of course, if I do a printf, I have
percent d dollars in my account.
And then, I print the value of
balance if I compile and run.
In the terminal I have
$50, and then I have $10.
That's not what I really want to do.
Instead, I want the
computation to occur.
So I could say 50 minus 40,
which is correct, because 50
was the old value of balance minus 40.
And that makes 10, of course.
The thing here is I want
to use the same variable.
So it might look strange,
but look what I will do here.
I would replace 50 with balance.
And that, if you look at this
line the first time you see this,
it might look a little bit strange
because from a mathematical point
of view, it's not equality.
balance is not equal to balance minus 40
because this sign here is not equality.
This is assignment, and
this is quite different,
meaning that we first have to
retrieve the value balance.
So it would be 50, then we have
to do the calculation minus 40.
That makes 10.
And the result of the
calculation 10, then we
assign it to the variable balance.
And that's exactly what happens
when I compile and run the program.
You see, I have $10 in my
account after the calculation.
Let's continue to make sure you
understand what's happening here.
I will add $20 in my account.
For this, I do the same--
balance
And I assign what?
The old value of balance plus
20, and then I will printf.
I have percent d
dollars in my account.
Let's compile and run.
As you can see here, now
I have $30 in my account
because it calculated the old value
of balance that was 10 plus 20.
And the results, 10 plus
20 equals 30, the result
we assign it to the
same variable balance.
And then we print it.
Let's continue with an
expense of $30, for example.
So that would make the
instruction balance equals
meaning I assign a new value, and the
new value is the old value of balance,
minus 30.
And then let me copy paste
this printf just here.
And let's compile and run this program.
Now I have $0 in my account.
$0 with an S, we'll see later on
how to test a certain variable
and printf a different sentence here.
We would like to printf.
$0 without a S, of course.
But we will see that
in the next sections.
So here, I will just do it manually.
And I will get rid of the dollar
with an S in the sentence here.
So that's how you create a variable,
and you put a first value in it.
And that's how you use it again,
meaning that you retrieve the old value.
You do a calculation, and the
result of the calculation,
you're assigning to the same variable.
So you can try by yourself by
putting different numbers here.
And you can even try to
multiply by 2 the balance
or try to use multiple times the
balance, the old value of the balance,
and try to understand
what's happening here
when you compile and run the program.
It's your turn now.