PROFESSOR: Let me show you the most
common errors when you use variables
with a compiler.
Here we have a simple program
that do a declaration here
of a variable, and then a definition.
And then we use it here.
If we compile and run,
we have in the terminal,
I have $40 dollars in my account.
Good.
Let's try to forget the
type definition here-- int.
So I only have the name of the
variable for the declaration, which
is quite an error.
If I compile, well, I get
multiple messages here.
Let me copy-paste to
understand what's happening.
First one is error, use of
undeclared identifier balance,
and this is line number three.
Indeed, line number three, there
is only the name of the variable.
So the compiler thinks that we
want to use a variable that exists,
that was already declared,
but it's not declared
because, we didn't defined the
type, which means that
we forgot to put int
to declare the type of the variable.
All right, so that's the first error.
If I compile now, it should be OK.
Yeah. It's run OK.
Second one I want to show you
is I forget the definition.
So I just get rid of this line,
and I have only the declaration.
And then we use the variable.
If I compile, then I
have also messages here.
Let me copy paste to show
you what's happening.
Going back to Edit mode
Here it's a warning--
warning, variable balance is
uninitialized when used here.
So you can see here that
when we use the variable--
well, we use it, but we
didn't put any value in it.
So what's happening here
is that by default, it
will put a 0 because we
didn't put any value.
This is absolutely not true with
standard compilers of C,
professional C compiler, they
won't put any value at all.
So you would have a random value.
So you'll have to be very, very
careful if you have this warning.
And if you use variables that are not
defined or you forget to put a value,
then in the codecast,
and in some compilers,
sometimes it will have
a 0 by default. This
is absolutely not true with all the
compilers, professional compilers.
It will have random values.
So it's very important to see
this warning and to correct them
when you have them.
So here, when you use a
variable that is uninitialized,
well, you should initialize it.
Meaning that you should
put a value, meaning
that you should define --definition--
define a value for the
first time initialization.
All right.
So now if I compile
and run, it works OK.
Something else-- if you use lower
case and upper case and you mix them--
for example here, let's
put a B uppercase.
Compile.
File and here we have multiple messages.
Let me copy paste them.
The first error is use of
undeclared identifier balance,
and look at here what's written--
did you mean balance with a B uppercase?
So it's pretty smart
here, because it knows
that you have a declaration of
a variable with a B uppercase.
The other one we won't
go into the details.
So here we can see directly that
we have to use a lowercase B. I guess
if we do the same with
definition, if I compile,
will I have the same kind of messages?
Use of undeclared identifier balance?
Did you mean balance
with a B, lowercase?
So this is quite explicit and
would be very easy to figure out.
Also, something else-- if I
declare one with a B lowercase,
and declaration two, and another
one with a B uppercase, then I
define the first one, and
I define a second one,
and then I use the first
and the second one.
Look what happens here
if I compile and run.
Where you can see that
it is case sensitive,
meaning that we have two
variables, one with a b lowercase,
one with a B uppercase, and
both of them are working.
So you have to be very sure of using
lower or uppercase letters when
you name the variables.
That's pretty much all I have to
say when you use the variables,
and all the different
errors you can have.
Maybe you can try to have
a different kind of error.
So try to do something
here to get an error
and try to see if you
understand the error.
You should try to generate new kind
of errors and tell us in the forum
if you found some of them.