We have now learned
how to create variables
and assign values to them.
I want to return to a very important point
that distinguishes the codecast tool,
that we are working in it right now
that we're using  to record this lectures
and that you are using to watch this lectures
and other tools that you might use later on
for C programming purposes.
Let's start by reviewing how to
declare and assign values to variables.
To declare a variable with type int
for integer type variable
and then the variable name
I'll just call it variable for now
So this is also called the variable declaration.
In order to assign a value to the variable
we then type the variable name
an equal sign
and the value that we wish to put into the variable
so "2" for example
This is the assignment
or we can call that a definition
or because it's the first time
that variable gets a value,
we also call that the initialization.
All is good.
But what happens right after
this line has been executed?
So the variable has been declared
but we have not yet assigned a value to it.
And that's where Codecast differs from other tools
that you might use later on.
Codecast automatically
assigns a value of 0 to the variable
after it has been declared.
So, at this stage,
in Codecast, variable will have the value 0.
This is not true
in other C programming utilities.
In particular, this is not true
in the tools like Taskgrader
that we'll be using to validate the code
that you submit in this MOOC.
And so this is not something to get used to
it's a nice feature of Codecast
but not something to get used to.
Instead, whenever you declare a variable,
you also should initialize it right away.
So that you will never find yourself
in this situation where a variable has been declared
but not initialized.
Whereas Codecast automatically initializes it at 0
other tools will not.
So what would variable be
in one of these other tools?
It turns out variable is just a memory box.
So what happens when you declare a variable?
Space in memory is reserved to hold
whatever you place into that variable.
But whatever was sitting in that memory location
from a previous run of a program
or from who knows what else was just happening
that would then be interpreted
as the current value of your variable.
So you've got to make sure
that you've overwrite it with the variable
value that you actually want to store in there
rather than keeping in there
whatever garbage just left
from a previous program execution.
So this is really important
in particular in Taskgrader,
that tool we use to validate your code,
variables will not be automatically initialized.
So best practice:
whenever you declare a variable
you also initialize it.
In fact this is so important
that you can actually do this in one step.
So you can actually type int
variable equals 2
and that is a variable declaration
and initialization
all in one step.
Then nothing can go wrong.
Even codecast can't get in your way and do anything for you.
This one line declares
and initializes a variable
all in one step.