Next, we'll learn how to
add comments to your code.
Comments are there to help you
explain to yourself and others
how your code is working.
Because often, it can happen
when you look at your own code
five weeks after you wrote it, you
can't really understand it anymore.
So comments are very important to
help explain what your code does.
Here again, we see the
program we wrote earlier,
which writes BlahBlehBlih three times to
the screen and then BlohBlue six times
on a new line.
So we wanted to add some comments here.
For example, right here, we would,
for example, type two forward slashes.
That tells that a comment is coming.
You can ignore this for
the compiler purposes.
This is only for the reader.
So we might type something
like, "A for loop
that prints BlahBlehBlih three times."
And you can see that
the editor automatically
chose a different color
for this text that I typed
right here, because it's a comment.
And so that stands out in my editor.
Another comment I might want
to add is when the loop ends.
So you could type something
like "End of for loop."
Also that we want to start a new line.
So "start new line" might be another
thing you might want to type here.
And again, you can see the color of
this text is different in the editor
because it's a comment.
And then you might want to
add another comment here.
"For loop that prints
BlohBluh six times".
All of these are comments
started by two forward slashes.
And these are one line comments.
And they won't influence the
execution of the program at all.
So if I compile this now
and then run the code,
nothing has changed whatsoever.
What has changed, however, is
that I added comments to my code
so that I can later better
understand how my code operates.