PROFESSOR: I'm going to show you how to
do a simple calculation using integers
with addition, substraction,
multiplication, and parentheses.
We won't see the division for now
because it's a special case in C,
and it has a special behavior.
We'll see that after.
So let's start with a simple
calculation with a printf.
3 plus 2 equals--
then I will output the result
with percent d. And 3 minus 2
equals percent d, and 3 times 2
equals percent d and then backslash n.
And then after the quote, I
have to do my calculation.
So the first percent d is to output
the calculation that is 3 plus 2.
And then with a comma, I
do the second parameter.
That is 3 minus 2.
And then with a comma, the third
parameter is 3 multiplied by 2.
And then semi-colon at the end.
Let's compile and run the program.
3 plus 2 equals 5, and 3 minus 2
equals 1, and 3 times 2 equals 6.
Great.
Let's try another example here with
3 plus 2 times 3 equals percent d.
And then I will use the parentheses.
So if I open a parenthesis
within the quote,
then the closing parenthesis is not
written automatically by the editor
because we are within the quotes.
And this is special
behavior of the editor.
So 3 plus 2 within parentheses
times 3 equals percent d
and then backslash n to have a new line.
And then I have to do a
comma with a parenthesis.
So the first one is 3 plus 2 times 3.
And then I come out
with another parameter--
parenthesis.
As you can see here, when I typed
the opening parenthesis, then
the closing one is automatically
written by the editor
because we are outside of the quotes.
So be aware of that.
So within the parentheses,
we have 3 plus 2.
And we do times 3.
Right.
Let's try that.
Compile and run.
So 3 plus 2 times 3 equals 9, and 3 plus
2 times 3 equals 15 with the parentheses.
So let me put some other examples
for you that I will copy paste,
and that you can test by yourself.
So here, we have different
options with different types
of calculation with different
types of parentheses,
as you can see here,
while I compile and run.
And look at the examples,
output in the terminal.
So we have 2 times 8 minus 2
times 7 minus 4 equals minus 2.
And then we have different outputs
depending where we put the parentheses.
So you can try by yourself.
And try to put different parentheses
or different calculation,
and try to have your outputs.
Don't forget that if you have multiple
percent d in the printf, for example,
here we have three of them, then
you have to have three parameters.
It needs three commas, first
one to separate with a quote,
second one to separate the
first parameter with the second,
and the third to separate
the second with third.
Do your own calculation right
now with this codecast.
Try it.