PROFESSOR: So far we have
learned about variables.
And we have learned about loops.
I will now show you how to use
variables in conjunction with loops.
To do so, let's look at
the following scenario.
Suppose I'm taking a hike in the forest.
And I'm hiking for, say, nine miles.
Every mile I pick up three hazelnuts.
And I'd like to print out how many
nuts I have in total, after each mile.
So to do so, I need to
store two quantities--
how many nuts I have at any point in
time, and how far I have traveled.
So let's do that.
Let's declare two
integer-type variables, one
of them being the number of hazelnuts.
And whenever we declare a variable,
remember we should also initialize it.
And initially I have none.
I haven't collected any hazelnuts yet.
And then another variable, that
stores how far I have hiked so far.
So distanceTraveled.
And again, at the beginning of my hike
I haven't traveled any kind of distance
yet.
So now every mile--
at mile 0, at mile 1, mile
2, at mile 3, and so forth,
I would like to print out how many
hazelnuts I have collected so far.
That sounds like a loop to me.
So let's paste in our
typical loop statement--
for i equals 0, i less than 9.
I'm going to repeat
this loop nine times.
That's why I put in 9 here--
i plus plus.
And we're going to need a closing
brace, at the end of this loop.
And then we can put something in there.
Now remember, whenever we have this
loop, the i that you see in here
is actually a variable.
We haven't really spoken
of it as a variable.
But I need to declare
this variable, just like I
need to declare any other old variable.
So we'll understand that more later.
For now, let's put it up there.
So here's my loop.
9 times I want to repeat something.
What is it that I want to repeat?
Well, I'd like to print out
how many hazelnuts I have.
So I need a printf statement, that
says that at so and so many miles,
and this percent d will be
replaced by 0, 1, 2, 3, and so forth.
So at percent d miles, I have--
and then whatever many hazelnuts
I have.
And let's start a new
line after each statement,
so we can read it more easily.
So now we can put in what these percent
d's should be replaced with.
What's the distance traveled
for the number of miles?
So distanceTraveled right here.
And for the number of hazelnuts, I
call that variable numberOfHazelnuts
And that's it.
So that's a printf
statement, that prints out
how many hazelnuts I have
at a certain distance.
But now I need to
update these variables.
Initially, I initialized them as 0.
But they don't stay 0.
After the first mile, I have
actually collected some hazelnuts.
So I need to change what's
stored in numberOfHazelnuts
as well as change my distance traveled.
So after each printf statement,
I need to actually increased
distance traveled by 1, so that I'm
getting ready for the next printf
statement.
So, how do I do that?
I write distanceTraveled equals
And now I need to state
an output statement.
distanceTraveled plus 1.
And that looks really weird, right?
That doesn't seem mathematically true.
You can't say distanceTraveled
equals distanceTraveled plus 1.
But remember, this equal sign
is not a mathematical equality,
it's an assignment statement.
It means that we take the right-hand
side, evaluate what's on the right,
and assign the result of the
evaluation to the variable on the left.
So the first time we're in
this loop, distanceTraveled
is still 0, from my initialization.
So this variable here
has the value of 0.
We've taken that 0 by adding 1 to it.
So the right-hand side evaluates to 1.
And that value is now assigned
to distanceTraveled.
In other words, distanceTraveled
is updated with the value 1,
if it previously was 0.
If it previously was 1, then it would
be updated with a value 2, and so forth.
So this statement updates distanceTraveled,
by increasing it by 1.
Similarly, my numberOfHazelnuts
needs to be updated.
And how does it need to be updated?
Well, I collect three hazelnuts
for every mile that I travel.
So I need to add 3 to the
current numberOfHazelnuts,
in order to get the new
number of hazelnuts.
numberOfHazelnuts plus 3.
And now I have upgraded both of my
variables, and my loop is complete.
I'm printing how many hazelnuts
I have at a certain mile.
And then I'm updating my distanceTraveled
and my numberOfHazelnuts,
to get ready for the next printf.
Let's compile and run this code.
And it says at 0 miles I have 0
hazelnuts, and a lot of other stuff.
Let's go through this slowly.
Remember, initially the
numberOfHazelnuts is 0,
and the distanceTraveled is 0.
That's how I enter my loop.
So the first time I get to this printf
statement, distanceTraveled is 0,
and numberOfHazelnuts is 0.
And that's why it
prints out at 0 miles I
have 0 hazelnuts-- the first statement
you see in the terminal window.
Next, I update distanceTraveled by
adding 1 to the old value of
distanceTraveled.
So 0 plus 1 is 1.
distanceTraveled now has the value 1.
And the numberOfHazelnuts is updated
by adding 3 to the old value of 0.
So 0 plus 3 is 3.
So distanceTraveled and numberOfHazelnuts
now have the value of 1 and 3
respectively.
And a loop means that
these three statements
are being repeated over
and over, and over again.
So next I get back to
this printf statement.
But this time the new values
are going to be printed.
So it's going to print out
at 1 mile I have 3 hazelnuts.
And that's what you see in the
second line that got printed out.
Then, distanceTraveled
is updated again.
Now it becomes 2.
numberOfHazelnuts is updated
to have the value is 6.
And we get back to the next iteration
of the loop, with a printf statement.
It now prints, at 2
miles I have 6 hazelnuts.
And it keeps going and going, and
going and going like that, until I
get to, at 8 miles I have 24 hazelnuts.
Why's that stop at 8?
I wanted this loop repeated nine times.
Well, it actually did repeat nine
times, because we started at 0.
So 0 was printed out during the
first iteration of the loop.
One gets printed out during the
second iteration, and so forth.
8 gets printed out during the
ninth iteration of the loop.
So the loop was indeed
executed nine times.
So this is how we can use
variables inside loops.