PROFESSOR: Let's study how we can
print and manipulate integer numbers
using the printf statement.
Let's start with an example.
Suppose I wanted to print out to the
screen if I have 3 bills worth
$5 each.
And I have-- what do I have? $15.
And I can totally do that.
If I run this, and I'll do that in a
second, it'll will print to screen.
If I have 3 bills worth
$5 each, then I have $15.
Printf is called a function that
takes a parameter inside parentheses.
So printf is the name of the function.
And we have an opening parenthesis here
and a closing parenthesis right there.
And in between those comes a parameter.
This particular parameter here
is called a string of characters.
Why is it called a string of characters?
Well, because it's literally
one character after the next
that I put in there.
First an I, then an f, and then space,
another I, and so forth, until I
get to this 3, which is also simply
interpreted as a character that's
going to be printed to the screen.
But let's compile this and run the code.
And indeed it prints out.
If I have 3 bills worth
$5 each, then, I have $15.
Let's go back to Edit mode.
The printf function is
actually way more powerful.
It allows us to print out and format
numbers in a number of different ways.
So let me show you how.
We can replace each
number with a percent d.
And I'll explain why we are doing that.
d, it stands
for an integer number.
So if we wanted to print
other types of numbers,
like one that have decimal places
we use something else.
This percent d is called
a format specifier.
It specifies that wherever
I've put the percent
d inside my string of characters,
I wish a number to appear.
But how do I tell C what number I
want printed in place of the percent d
format specifier?
Those numbers get passed in as
additional parameters to the printf
function.
To do so, all you have to
do is put a comma right
after the string of characters is over.
And then you place the
numbers that you would
like to replace the percent ds with.
So the first percent d here,
I wanted that to say 3.
So I put that 3 after
the comma right here.
Then next percent d, I wanted that to
say 5, because I want three $5 bills.
So I put a comma after the three,
then a five, and another comma.
And now comes the next
percent d. So that makes $15.
So I want this last percent
d to be replaced with a 15.
And so the way this is
understood, I'm giving
the printf function for parameters.
Namely, the first one
is the whole string.
The second one is that three.
The third one is the five.
And the fourth one is this 15.
And what happens when I
compile and run this program
is that the first percent d gets
replaced with the first number that
comes right after the string.
The second percent d gets
replaced with a second number
that comes right after the string.
And the third percent d gets
replaced with a third number
that comes after the string.
So let's compile and run this code.
And indeed, it says again, if I
have three bills worth $5 each,
then I have $15.
But you can do even more.
Let's go back to edit.
We can in fact have C do
the computation for us here.
I just put 15 because I
know 3 times 5 equals 15.
But the function is powerful enough
for me to be able to put 3 times
5 right there in place of the 15.
The times is simply the star character.
3 star 5 stands for 3 times 5.
And what's going to happen?
The 3 times 5 will be
evaluated as 15, and then
placed in place of this
percent d right here.
Let's check it out.
Compile and run.
And indeed, it says again if I
have 3 bills worth $5 each,
then I have $15.
So this is how you can
manipulate and print, and start
to do simple calculations
with integer numbers.