PROFESSOR: I'm going to show you how
to read multiple things from the input
using a for repetition loop.
First, I'm going to need
a variable, howMany.
Let's put 0 for the moment.
howMany is how many things, how many
items I want to read from the input.
And I will need the sum,
because the thing I want to do
is, I want to add all
the things that were
read from the input and output
the sum of all the things read.
Then I will need a third variable,
which is the number that was read.
And I'm going to show you how to
use a for loop, for repetition loop
to do multiple scanf to read what's
inside the terminal multiple times.
So here, before I start
the repetition loop,
I have to ask how many items
will be read from the input.
So I ask this with a scanf.
First, I can put a printf.
And I can ask, how many
items do you want to add?
Let's say that.
Right.
So then I do the scanf
%d, and I read the value,
and I put the value in
the variable howMany.
So that would be ampersand howMany.
Right.
So now I know how many
times I want to repeat
another scanf that will read all of
the stuff I put in the input terminal.
So I can use the for repetition loop.
And I will repeat, how many times?
Well, howMany, which is
the variable howMany.
What will I repeat in this loop?
Well, I will read all of
the values from the input.
So that would be a
scanf, again, with a %d.
And I will put what I have read
in the variable numberRead.
And this number that I've just
read, I will first printf it.
I have read %d from the input
terminal, and then \n.
And the %d is the numberRead.
And then, what I want to do, is I want
to add all of the things that I've read
and to put the result in the sum.
So the sum will be--
well, the old sum.
For example here, at
the beginning, it's 0.
Then it will be the
new value of the sum.
And I will add to the sum the number
that I've just read from the input.
And then I will printf sum
equals %d, and new line.
And the %d is the value
of the variable sum.
All right.
Let's try to compile
and run this program.
So first, I have, "How many
items do you want to add?"
I want to add three items.
And I type Enter.
Then I go into the repetition loop.
And as you can see here,
the sum is equal to 0.
The numberRead, first, is
equal to 0, and i is 0.
It's the first time I repeat
the instructions in the loop.
So the first item I want to add is 10.
So I put 10 in the
terminal, and I put Enter.
And see that the instructions,
where the printf, then the new sum
calculation, and another printf.
And the output is, "I have read
10 from the input terminal,
and the sum equals 10."
And then we repeat the instructions,
and we go back to the scanf.
So the second item I want to add is 4.
So I put 4, and I type Enter.
And then in the output, "I have
read 4 from the input terminal,
and the sum equals 14."
Why?
Because the old sum was
10, and then we added
4 that was just read from the input.
So the sum equals 14 now.
And then we repeat a third time, because
how many items do we want to add?
Three.
So it is the third time
we do the for loop.
And here, I want to add 2.
And then I press Enter.
And in the output, I can see, "I
have read 2 from the input terminal,
and the sum equals 16," which is the old
sum value, 14, plus 2, which equals 16.
So now I want, really, you
to test it by yourself.
It's very important here that
you test this program yourself
and that you understand
what's happening here,
what we do, exactly,
when we repeat the instructions here.
You have to understand that we read
a number, and then with the number
that we've just read, we
add it to the sum variable.
But the sum variable is also used here.
So we have the old sum variable,
and we added the new read number.
And we really have to understand
what's happening here.
So please try it by yourself
with your own numbers
and try to understand
what's happening here.
For example, try to
understand this for loop.
And you can see here that I
changed with howMany variable, so
that we can repeat a
certain number of times that
will be defined with the value
that is read from the first scanf,
answering the questions, "How
many items do we want to add?"
And this is the answer
from the input terminal.
The user said how many times he
wants to repeat this for loop.
And within the repetition, then,
you have multiple instructions.
So let's try it by yourself.
And let's try it with
other values as the input.
Do it right now.