PROFESSOR: We will now learn
how to memorize an integer value
and to use it later on in a program.
To do so, we use what's
called variables.
One could think of variables
as little memory boxes.
These memory boxes contain the
things we'd like to remember
and are stored in the computer's memory.
Right now, what we'd like to
memorize is an integer value.
Let's look at this simple program here.
What it does is it has
three printf statements,
and it prints out three strings
of characters and has some %d,
some format specifiers in them that are
replaced by the numbers that we place
as additional parameters
into the printf statement.
So for example, this first printf
statement will print I am and then it
will replace %d with a 17, so
it'll print I am 17 years old.
On the next line, it
will print In eight years,
I will be 17 plus eight,
which equals 25 years old.
And then in the third line, it'll
print, 11 years ago, I was 17 minus 11,
which is 6 years old.
So let's compile and run this just
to make sure everything's good.
And indeed, I'm 17 years old.
In eight years I'll be 25 years old,
and 11 years ago I was six years old.
Let's go back to edit mode.
And suppose I want to
memorize this 17 right here.
To do so, I need to
first create a variable.
So a memory box with
room to store the 17 in.
And then, I need to place
that 17 into this memory box.
So let's write down two comments
of the things I need to do.
I need to create a variable
to store an integer value.
And next, I need to assign
a value to that variable.
And how do I do these two things?
In C, an integer is
called an int, just int.
The abbreviation int
is used for integer.
So to create a variable that
can hold integer values,
I type int to tell C that's
what I want to store.
Then a space, and then I need to
assign a name to my memory box.
And since I want to store my age in
there, why don't I call this name age?
This line int age semi-colon
creates a memory box
to which I can later on
refer by the name of age.
Next, I need to place a
value into age, namely my 17.
To do so, I type the
name of the variable
on the left, then an equal sign.
And this equal sign means in C
that I want to put a value into age.
I want to initialize the
variable age with a number.
And that number goes on the right
hand side followed by a semi-colon.
So this is not a mathematical
equal sign that compares
whether the two sides are equal.
It's called an assignment statement.
We're assigning the value
17 to the variable age,
meaning we're placing that
17 into this memory box
so that we can remember it later.
So now, how do I use the fact that
I've stored the 17 into the variable age?
I can simply go ahead and
replace the 17 everywhere
in my program with this
variable age, and what
happens when the program runs this,
it sees, OK, a variable shows up.
That means I need to go ahead
and find the value that's stored
in that variable and put it right here.
So when the program runs,
it'll replace age with 17,
and then it'll put the
17 in place of the %d,
and it will still print
I am 17 years old.
I do the same thing for this 17.
I put age instead of 17 and also
here, I put age instead of 17.
Let's run this program and
make sure it actually works.
So we compile and then
hit the run button.
And it says, indeed, I am 17 years old.
So indeed, up here this %d was replaced
with a value that's stored in age.
In %d years, that's eight years, in
eight years I will be %d years old.
That's age plus 8.
age has the value 17.
17 plus 8  equals 25.
And finally, 11 years ago I was age minus
11, age has the value 17, 17 minus 11
equals 6.
So I was six years old.
So it worked just like we envisioned.
Let's go back to edit mode.
So why is this so useful?
Well, I can now actually
change the age quite easily.
Suppose I'm no longer 17 years
old but I'm rather 29 years old.
So I change the assignment value here.
age equals 29 instead of h equals 17.
And that's all I have to do.
I don't have to go change
the 17 that used to sit here
and make that a 29 and the
one that used to sit here
make that a 29 and the one that
used to sit here and make it a 29.
I simply change age in
one place of my program
and when I now compile
and run the program,
it has replaced age with 29 everywhere.
So in 8 years, I
will be 37 years old.
11 years ago I was 18 years old.
Let's do this one more
time just for fun.
So we go back to edit.
And let's say I am 47 years old.
I can compile and run this code.
And all of the sudden, age has the value
47 wherever I use it in my program.
So this makes using and
reusing a value really easy,
because you can change
that value in one place
rather than have to find
every place in your program
where you actually use
the specific value.
So this is how to create
and initialize variables
and how to use them in your
program in the case of integers.