PROFESSOR: I'm going to show you now how
to read characters from the user input.
Suppose I wanted the user
to enter a character,
and then store it in a variable.
And the variable is
named letter. Then I need
a variable of type character.
And let's call it letter.
Next, I should probably tell
the user to enter a letter.
And then I can read what
they enter using scanf.
The format specifier for
a letter is a percent c,
as we already know from
using the printf function.
And in order to store this letter
that was read from the keyboard,
from the user input,
I need to specify here
with an ampersand and variable,
in which it's going to be stored.
Again, I need that ampersand
character, just as I did for numbers.
Now I should also verify
that everything went fine.
So I print letter percent c, just to
verify that everything went fine.
And it's letter that I read.
Let's compile and run this.
Please enter a letter.
Let's enter a. I read the
letter a. So everything's good.
In fact, I can even use multiple percent
c's and one scanf statement.
Suppose I want the user
to enter two letters--
letter2.
So please enter two letters.
And I would put a second
percent c right there.
And it's letter, and letter2.
And then I read the letter.
I should really print them both out--
percent c, letter and letter2.
And I can compile this, and run.
Please enter two letters: a, b. I
read the letters a and b. Perfect.
Now notice, I did not put a
space between my two letters.
Characters behave differently from
numbers in the scanf function.
Scanf, when dealing with numbers,
automatically skipped whitespace.
And I could put in as many spaces
between numbers as I wanted to.
That is not true for characters.
A space would be considered
just another character.
Let me demonstrate that to you.
If I run this program again, and put a
space between my two characters here,
then it says I read the
letters a and space.
Because that's the space that it read.
It didn't read the b.
It didn't get there.
I didn't ask it to
read a third letter.
So that's the characters a and space.
So if I actually wanted the user to
separate their letters by a space,
I would have to first of
all tell them that-- please
enter two letters separated by a space.
And then I would have to put that
space right here in that format string,
in the scanf function.
That way would indicate
to C that I first
want the user to enter a character, then
a space, and then another character.
Let's give this a try.
I compile, and I run.
These are the two letters
separated by a space--
a space b. Right now, it actually works.
Similarly, if I didn't want
them to have a space there,
but I want them separated by a
comma, I can do that as well.
And then I'd need to similarly
put that
right here in the format string.
So now I'm expecting the user
to enter a character, a comma,
and another character.
Let's compile and run.
Now I enter a comma b. No space--
that space will be an extra character.
And indeed, I read the
letters a and b. Typically,
you just read one character at
a time, or specify exactly how
you wanted the user to enter those.
So now you know how to read
characters from the user input.