PROFESSOR: Let's introduce
a new type of variable.
This type is the character variable.
So to declare a variable that is of
type character, I just type C-H-A-R.
And then the name of the
variable, like letter.
And that's how you declare
a character variable.
How do you assign this variable?
Well, let me show you.
You always use the assignment operator
and then we use the simple quote.
So I typed the simple
quote, and as you can see,
the editor is giving me the
closing quote corresponding.
And between these simple quotes,
I can put a character, like a
for example.
So that's how you define, or
initialize, or assign a character value.
Now, how do you print in the
output, this type of variable?
Well, in the printf, I can say
the letter is and I use the format
percent c for character.
And then, as for integer,
I put the variable name.
So for example here, letter.
Let's try it.
Let's compile and run the program.
And the terminal, you see
the output, the letter is a.
So that's how you declare
a character variable.
And with simple quotes, how you
define or assign a correct value
to a character variable and
with the percent c
this is how you print this variable.
Let's try it by yourself and replace
it with the character of your choice.