PROFESSOR: I'm going to
show you how to comment some
of the lines that include code already.
So we have two ways of doing that.
First is to put the comment
at the end of the instruction.
For example, here we have
a program with two loops,
then the first one is repeating
three times BlahBlehBlih
And then we have a new
line with a printf,
and the second one is repeating
six times, as you can see here,
BlohBluh So if I compile and
execute, then we have BlahBlehBlih
three times and BlohBluh six times.
And to separate the
two, we have a new line.
All right, so let me
go back to Edit mode.
So I want to comment this code.
So what I can do is, at
the end of each code line,
I can put any comment I want to
make it clearer for someone
that will read the code.
So here, beginning of the main.
Well, this doesn't serve you.
You don't have to say that.
This line, for example, I can say
specific line used to repeat with the for.
This is the start of the
first loop, and this is
the first instruction inside the loop.
And this is the second
instruction inside the loop.
And this is the third
And what is this one?
This is the end of the first loop.
Well, that prints new line.
And this is a second loop, so
the beginning of a second loop.
And this is the first
instruction of the second loop.
And this is the second
instruction with the second loop.
All right.
And this is the end of the second loop.
That's how you put some comment
at the end of the instruction.
So these ones are very simple comments
just to show you how it works.
So it's just a double slash
at the end of the instruction,
so after the semicolon.
Or here, as you can see,
it's the beginning of a loop,
so I put it just after the opening
brace, or here, the same for the main
just after.
So at the end of the line, if you
finish the line with a double slash,
then the rest is a comment.
As you can see here
it's in different colors
to say that it's a comment.
Something else that
I want to show you is
that you can comment very easily
one line so that it is not executed.
So by the way, here, if I
compile and run the program,
it is exactly the same
behavior and the same output
because it doesn't change
the behavior of the program.
But now I'm going to show
you how you can comment
one line to change the behavior.
For example, for the
first repetition loop,
I can comment the first printf by
putting two slash before the printf.
And as you can see, the printf changes
the color and is now a comment,
so it will not be executed anymore.
So if I compile and run, you
can see that instead of having
BlahBlehBlih, we have BlehBlih.
I can do the same with
Bleh, for example.
I compile and run, and
now for the first loop
we only have Blih Blih Blih
instead of
BlahBlehBlih because I just
commented the two first lines.
So you get the point.
Anytime you want to
do some testing, it's
very good to comment some of the lines
to see the behavior of the program.
So that's a good way to debug a program.
Here I just commented the
Bloh line in the second loop,
so I only have the Bluh.
And here I have only Blih
that is not commented and Bluh
that is not commented.
And that's a way to debug a program
so that you can comment and uncomment
some of the lines very easily and
see what's happening if you have
a certain bug to focus more on the bug.
So you can try by yourself
and comment some of the line,
but be careful, because if
you comment, for example,
the beginning of the
first loop, the for,
then you will have some
syntactic error because you
have the closing brace for the
for, but the opening brace for the
for is commented.
So that's a syntactic error.
So you have to make sure
that, if you comment a line,
you still keep a certain behavior
that is correct to debug your program.
So go ahead and try to
comment some of the lines here
or uncomment some of the
lines and see if you can
play with the comments within the code.