PROFESSOR: Now that we
know how to add comments
to our code on individual
lines or at the end of a line,
we'll learn another way to
put comments in our code.
This time, comments that
go over multiple lines.
Here we have a simple
program that contains
a for loop that will repeat
what's inside it three times.
Inside the for loop printing
BlahBlehBlihBlohBluh and a space
after the last one, and then
we're repeating that three times.
So we expect one line on which we see
BlahBlehBlihBlohBluh three times
separated by spaces.
Let's quickly compile and
run this code, and indeed,
we see BlahBlehBlihBlohBluh repeated **
three times separated by spaces.
Now let's go to edit,
and suppose we wanted
to explain what this program
actually does to someone.
To do so over multiple lines, we
would start a multi-line comment
by typing forward slash and star.
The end of a multi-line
comment is indicated
with a star and a forward slash.
So the same two symbols,
just in the opposite order.
Anything that goes in between
is considered a comment
and will be ignored by the compiler.
So for example, we might type
here, this program uses a for loop.
And suppose I wanted
to start a new line.
I simply hit Return here, and the
comment continues on the next line.
So this program uses
for a loop to print out
a new line BlahBlehBlihBlohBluh three times.
And you can see the color of
my text has changed again,
indicating that this is a comment.
Anything between slash star and
star slash is considered a comment.
So this won't affect the
execution of my program at all.
It's just there to explain
what my program does.
Let's quickly make sure
this actually works.
Let's compile and run, and indeed the
program acts exactly as it did before.
Let's go back to edit mode, and
let's see what else we can do.
Suppose you discovered that you actually
didn't want these first four printf
statements in this for loop, you just
want it to print Bluh three times.
Well I could put a slash star in
front of the first printf statement
and a star slash behind the
fourth printf statement,
and now anything between the
slash star and the star slash
is considered a comment.
So all of these printf statements
are actually now considered comments
and will be ignored by the compiler.
In other words, the only printf
statement that will be executed
is this very last one.
Let's give this a try.
Compile and run the code.
And indeed it only
prints Bluh three times,
because we said we would
repeat this loop three times.
Let's go back to editing.
And let's get rid of
these comment signs now so
that our code is back
to where it was before.
If we now compile and run,
the code acts exactly the way
it did before, and prints
BlahBlehBlihBlohBluh three times in a row.
Suppose now I want to just get rid of
the third and fourth printf statement.
Well I can do that by starting a comment
before the first printf statement
I want to get rid of, and ending
that comment after the second one.
So now these two lines of code all
of a sudden appear as comments.
And what's going to happen
is we're going to print Blah
Bleh, we're going to skip Blih,
Bloh, and go right to Bluh.
So what do we expect the output to be?
We expect it to be BlahBlehBluh
space BlahBlehBluh space
BlahBlehBluh space,
because I'm simply missing
the Blih and the Bloh in the middle.
Let's compile the code and run.
And indeed BlahBlehBluh, BlahBlehBluh
BlahBlehBluh as we expected.
Let me go back to editing.
We can again remove these
commentary signs if we wish to.
And the code is back
to its original form.
So multi-line comment can be very useful
in quickly commenting out some code
that you just don't
want to currently use,
but you don't want to delete
the lines either, because you
might want to use the code again later.
Comments are very useful.