Just like you can print multiple
integers using just one printf
statement by simply using multiple
percent d format specifiers,
you can also read multiple integers
from the user input using one scanf
statement with multiple
percent d format specifiers.
Let's take a look at an example.
So if we want to read
multiple variables,
we need to declare multiple variables.
So how about we have one called
first, one called second,
then one called third.
Then, we should probably ask
the user to enter some numbers.
Please enter three integers.
And then we have a scanf, and we
simply put the percent d for the first,
a percent d for the second,
and then another percent d
for the third number we want to read.
And then after the format string, we
put a comma, and the first variable
with the ampersand sign in front of it.
The first variable is first, and
then another ampersand second,
and another ampersand third.
But that means that the
first number the user enters
will be stored in the
variable first, the second one
they enter will be stored in the
variable second, and the third one
they entered will be stored
in the variable third.
So let's print out what the user entered
and the values of these variables.
percent d for second,
and percent d for third.
And then we need to put in our
variables-- first, second, third.
OK.
Let's check this out.
Let's compile this, and let's run.
"Please enter three integers."
How about 5, 789, and 17.
"You entered 5 for first, 789
for second, and 17 for third."
So that worked perfectly.
I want to show you something
else that's possible, however.
So if we run this program again,
"please enter three integers,"
I could even hit the Return
key after each integer.
So I don't remember
what I just entered--
5, and then 678, and I am hitting
Return after each integer, so 34.
And it still worked just fine.
5 for the first, 678 for the
second, and 34 for the third.
I could even do this in
some kind of mixed fashion.
If I run this program again,
"enter three integers,"
I could enter the first one--
6-- and 32, and then hit Return,
and then enter a third integer here,
and it still will write all
these integers just fine.
What happens when C reads integers
or numbers from the user input
is it simply ignores white
space between numbers.
So as it gets ready to
read the second number,
it ignores all white space
before the second number.
We could go even a little bit further.
If run this program again, I
could even put some white spaces
in front of the first number
before I even enter anything.
And then maybe enter a 45, and then
a bunch of more spaces, and then 33,
and another space, then 75.
And it still writes all
those numbers correctly.
So when reading numbers, the scanf
function ignores white space,
so that's returned
characters, spaces, and such.
However, let me show you one more thing.
When I run this again--
and this time I put commas
between my integers--
that's not going to be good.
It writes the first number
just fine, but then it
got confused for the second
number, and got a 0 there, and then
0 for the third number
because the comma confused it.
In order for the user to
be able to enter commas,
you would have to specify that
in your scanf format string.
So we could do that.
If I specify that I want a
comma between these numbers,
I have to put that comma right there.
And then I could tell
the user, please enter
three integers separated by commas.
And now when I run the code-- compile
and run-- "enter three integers
separated by commas,"
I could enter 34, 76,
and I could still put
lots of spaces here.
And there we go.
And that worked again
because the comma is now
in the place where it was expected.
So you can read multiple inputs all
at once with one scanf statement,
and white space is ignored
when reading numbers.